<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>HaveBoyGirl.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://haveboygirl.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://haveboygirl.com</link>
	<description>Dallas Fertility Clinic &#38; Texas IVF Specialists</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:27:05 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>What You Need to Know  About Multiple Miscarriages</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-multiple-miscarriages/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 17:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=367</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>What You Need to Know About Multiple Miscarriages Common causes. Helpful tests. Promising treatments. Early pregnancy loss is so common that many people consider miscarriages to be a part of the reproductive process. But that doesn’t make the loss any easier to bear for couples hoping to raise a family. When early pregnancy loss occurs not just once—but multiple times—the emotional pain and concern can be even more traumatic. Yet, experiencing multiple miscarriages doesn’t mean that a couple will never be able to experience the joy of parenthood. &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-multiple-miscarriages/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-multiple-miscarriages/">What You Need to Know  About Multiple Miscarriages</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>What You Need to Know About Multiple Miscarriages</h1>
<p><b>Common causes. Helpful tests. Promising treatments.</b></p>
<p>Early pregnancy loss is so common that many people consider miscarriages to be a part of the reproductive process. But that doesn’t make the loss any easier to bear for couples hoping to raise a family.</p>
<p>When early pregnancy loss occurs not just once—but multiple times—the emotional pain and concern can be even more traumatic. Yet, experiencing multiple miscarriages doesn’t mean that a couple will never be able to experience the joy of parenthood. In fact, with the help of advanced testing and treatments, the majority of couples who have experienced recurrent pregnancy loss will indeed go on to achieve their dream of having a baby.</p>
<p><strong>What is recurrent pregnancy loss?</strong><br />
Recurrent pregnancy loss used to be defined as the occurrence of three or more consecutive miscarriages. However, the American Society of Reproductive Medicine has recently defined repeated miscarriage as the loss of two or more clinically recognized pregnancies before 20 weeks gestation. A “clinically recognized” pregnancy means the pregnancy has been visualized on an ultrasound.</p>
<p><strong>How common are multiple miscarriages?</strong><br />
Studies show that approximately 15 percent of all recognized pregnancies end in a miscarriage. About 5 percent of women will have two consecutive miscarriages, and approximately 1 percent of women will experience recurrent pregnancy loss.</p>
<p><strong>What causes recurrent pregnancy loss?</strong><br />
There are several factors that influence miscarriage rates, including the advancing age of the mother. For example, we know that pregnant women in their 40s will experience a much higher percentage of miscarriages than women in their 20s or early 30s.</p>
<p>Most pregnancy losses result from genetic abnormalities and are random events. The abnormality may come from the egg, the sperm, or the early embryo. Autoimmune, uterine, hormonal and immunological factors have also been linked to miscarriages. Lifestyle factors, such as cigarette smoking and cocaine use, have been reported to increase the incidence of miscarriages as well.</p>
<p><strong>What tests are available to help find the cause of repeated miscarriages?</strong><br />
If you have experienced one or more miscarriages, it is very important to see a doctor. A complete physical examination, including a pelvic exam, will be done. You may also have blood tests to detect problems with the immune system or hormone function. An infertility specialist can also rule out certain anatomic issues associated with miscarriages, such as uterine fibroids.</p>
<p>Genetic screening for both partners may be recommended to help identify potential genetic causes of recurrent pregnancy loss. Approximately 60 percent of early miscarriages are due to chromosomal abnormalities. This usually means the embryo carried an extra chromosome, was missing a chromosome, or had chromosome defects.</p>
<p>The good news is that recent studies show that, depending on the cause and treatment options, the chance for a successful future pregnancy after miscarriage is as high as 60-80 percent.</p>
<p><strong>What treatments are available for recurrent pregnancy loss?</strong><br />
Treatment options are based on the underlying cause of the repeated miscarriages. In the case of uterine fibroids, for example, surgery may be recommended. If testing revealed thyroid dysfunction, diabetes or a clotting disorder, medications will be prescribed.</p>
<p>If you have a chromosomal issue, genetic counseling may be recommended. IVF (in vitro fertilization) with special genetic testing called “preimplantation genetic testing” offers the best chance for a successful pregnancy.</p>
<p><strong>What is preimplantation genetic testing?</strong><br />
Preimplantation genetic testing (PGT) is a micromanipulation technique that allows fertility labs to test embryos from IVF for certain types of genetic conditions. PGT may be done to select unaffected embryos, which increases the odds of having children that will be healthy and have every opportunity to succeed in life.</p>
<p>For those who know that they carry a genetic predisposition for a painful or debilitating disease, such as sickle cell anemia or cystic fibrosis, ensuring that the disease will not be passed on to their children—and their children’s children—can also provide peace of mind.</p>
<p><strong>When should you see a specialist?</strong><br />
In the past, women were advised to wait until they had three or more consecutive miscarriages before making an appointment with a fertility specialist. That is no longer the rule. There’s no reason to wait it out before seeking answers and receiving appropriate treatments that could help you have a baby sooner.</p>
<p>According to the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, you should seek the care of an infertility specialist if you are unable to achieve pregnancy after 12 months of unprotected intercourse. If you are over the age of 35, the time of trying to conceive is reduced to six months. You should also seek the care of a specialist if you have had more than one miscarriage.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-multiple-miscarriages/">What You Need to Know  About Multiple Miscarriages</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oh, Sugar! How Diabetes and Prediabetes Affect Fertility</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/oh-sugar-how-diabetes-and-prediabetes-affect-fertility/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 19:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=310</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been trying to get pregnant with no luck, it may be time to have a simple blood test to determine if your glucose (blood sugar) levels are high. Over time, persistent high glucose levels may hurt your eyes, kidneys, nerves and heart. It can also lead to infertility. Here’s what you need to know – and what you can do – if you are prediabetic or diabetic and hoping to grow your family. First, the facts about blood sugar levels. Diabetes is a very common medical &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/oh-sugar-how-diabetes-and-prediabetes-affect-fertility/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/oh-sugar-how-diabetes-and-prediabetes-affect-fertility/">Oh, Sugar! How Diabetes and Prediabetes Affect Fertility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been trying to get pregnant with no luck, it may be time to have a simple blood test to determine if your glucose (blood sugar) levels are high. Over time, persistent high glucose levels may hurt your eyes, kidneys, nerves and heart. It can also lead to infertility. Here’s what you need to know – and what you can do – if you are prediabetic or diabetic and hoping to grow your family.</p>
<p><strong>First, the facts about blood sugar levels.</strong><br />
Diabetes is a very common medical condition today. According to the American Diabetes Association, there are 29 million people in the U.S. living with diabetes. Another 8.1 million people in the country have diabetes, but do not know it.</p>
<p>Type 2 diabetes is the most common form of the disease. If you have Type 2 diabetes, your body does not use insulin properly. This is called insulin resistance. At first, your pancreas makes extra insulin to make up for it. But, over time, it isn&#8217;t able to keep up and can&#8217;t make enough insulin to keep your blood glucose at normal levels.</p>
<p>Prediabetes is a condition that affects another 79 million Americans. With prediabetes, your glucose levels are higher than they should be—but not high enough to be diagnosed as diabetes. Prediabetes is a wake-up call for diabetes. However, it’s not too late to take actions to lower your risk for diabetes.</p>
<p><strong>Sugar ain’t so sweet when it comes to fertility.</strong><br />
Insulin is a hormone, and when a hormone is out of balance it can cause other hormones – such as estrogen, progesterone and testosterone – to be out of balance, too.</p>
<p>Diabetes alone does not prevent a woman from getting pregnant. In fact, if your diabetes is kept under control through proper diet, exercise and medication, it should not play a major role in your ability to conceive.</p>
<p>However, if your blood glucose levels are not under control, it can have several negative effects on your fertility as well as your ability to sustain a pregnancy. High blood sugar, for example, is a reason why an embryo sometimes fails to implant in the uterus. According to the American Diabetes Association, high glucose levels may increase a woman’s chance of miscarriage by as much as 30 to 60 percent.</p>
<p>Congenital fetal malformations occur more commonly in diabetic mothers with poorly controlled sugar levels. The most commonly affected areas for the fetus are cardiovascular, central nervous system, and genitourinary system. Poorly controlled sugar levels, especially during the third trimester, increase the risk for fetal macrosomia (overly large baby). This can lead to a difficult delivery, birth trauma, and abnormally low glucose levels for the baby after delivery.</p>
<p><strong>Are PCOS and diabetes kissing cousins?</strong><br />
Having too much insulin in the body can increase your risk for PCOS (polycystic ovary syndrome), a condition that affects approximately one in 10 women of childbearing age. Although it is not uncommon to have both diabetes and PCOS, women can have PCOS and not diabetes and vice versa.</p>
<p>Most women with PCOS grow small cysts on their ovaries, thus giving the disorder its name. These cysts are not harmful, but they do lead to changes in the hormonal pathways that produce eggs and prepare the uterus for pregnancy.</p>
<p>For women with PCOS, the ovaries make more androgens (male hormones) than normal. High levels of these hormones affect ovulation and can lead to symptoms like acne, excess body hair, weight gain and “belly fat.”</p>
<p>Among the most important reasons why becoming pregnant – or staying pregnant – may be more challenging for women with PCOS are unreliable, unpredictable or even absent ovulation. Several medications that stimulate ovulation can help women with PCOS to conceive. Another treatment option is in vitro fertilization (IVF), which offers the best chance of becoming pregnant in any given cycle.</p>
<p>In IVF, ovulation is induced with injectable fertility medications so that multiple eggs are produced. Healthy sperm are combined with the eggs in a laboratory. Three to five days after the egg retrieval procedure, the fertilized eggs, or embryos, are then transferred to the uterus through the vagina.</p>
<p><strong>Diabetes may affect a man’s fertility, too.</strong><br />
Recent research indicates that diabetes also can cause fertility issues in men. Scientists have found that DNA damage in the sperm of diabetic men is higher than in the sperm of men who do not have diabetes.</p>
<p>Certain diabetes complications can also contribute to infertility in men. Nerve damage from diabetes can lead to retrograde ejaculation whereby semen goes into the bladder, making it impossible to get to the woman’s reproductive organs. Erectile dysfunction is another diabetes complication that can lead to fertility problems for men.</p>
<p>IVF is an excellent option for many couples who struggle to conceive, due to diabetes, prediabetes and other medical conditions. Sometimes, one sperm may be injected into each egg in a technique called intracytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI). ICSI is often recommended if there is a problem with sperm quality or quantity. In ICSI, only a single healthy sperm is needed for each egg.</p>
<p><strong>What’s next?</strong><br />
If you have diabetes, talk to your doctor about what you can do to ensure a happy, healthy pregnancy. Keeping your blood sugar levels under control is key to a successful pregnancy.</p>
<p>If you suspect you have prediabetes or PCOS and haven’t been officially diagnosed, visit your doctor again for testing. Couples that have been trying to get pregnant for six months or more should seek the help of a fertility specialist.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/oh-sugar-how-diabetes-and-prediabetes-affect-fertility/">Oh, Sugar! How Diabetes and Prediabetes Affect Fertility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beth C</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/beth-c/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 17:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Testimonials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=246</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>My husband and I married in August of 2008. As I was 36, we tried to get pregnant immediately. We went to a fertility clinic in Frisco in hopes of making sure that this could happen. They recommended we do an IUI immediately with medication. It did not work, and in December of 2008 during a routine examination, they discovered my right ovary was enlarged with a tumor. It was removed within 4 days along with the right fallopian tube. The next year they recommended we go straight &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/beth-c/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/beth-c/">Beth C</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Beth-Cuevas-picture-300x240.jpg" alt="Beth C" width="300" height="240" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-247" hspace="20" srcset="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Beth-Cuevas-picture-300x240.jpg 300w, https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Beth-Cuevas-picture-1024x819.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />My husband and I married in August of 2008.  As I was 36, we tried to get pregnant immediately.  We went to a fertility clinic in Frisco in hopes of making sure that this could happen.  They recommended we do an IUI immediately with medication.  It did not work, and in December of 2008 during a routine examination, they discovered my right ovary was enlarged with a tumor. It was removed within 4 days along with the right fallopian tube.  The next year they recommended we go straight to IVF and we did our first one without success.  In 2010, we tried our second, third, and fourth with this clinic….  During the last cycle I was hyperstimulated and they still transferred the embryos.  Obviously, all four IVF cycles did not work.   In 2011 my husband and I looked into adoption, went to seminars, and even attended a full weekend of foster care, but he convinced me we should try one more time.  I work in the medical industry and a couple of the oncology gynecologists at Medical City knew my history and recommendeded Dr. Peng.  My husband and I met with him in the spring of 2011.  Literally everything changed at that point.  There was no rush.  Dr. Peng wanted to find out everything about my husband and myself.   All our bloodwork, tests, etc.  He discovered a clotting disorder I have and many other reasons as to why we had not been successful in having a baby.  Dr. Peng would not progress forward until he was completely sure I could carry a pregnancy to term.  He reviewed all my charts and realized the termination of my embryos and exactly when they should be transferred.  In January of 2012, we underwent our 5th IVF with Dr. Peng and according to my history and medical records he did a 3 day transfer which resulted in the birth of my beautiful twin daughters, Avery and Brooks, on October 10, 2012.  Dr. Peng had adjusted medication, past history, everything….to ensure this was a success.  Now most people at this point would be happy, but my husband and I thought we needed to try for a son.  So in the fall of 2013, we started the process again with Dr. Peng for our 6th IVF and were informed over the Christmas break I was indeed pregnant.  We were told it was another girl by our OBGYN and we were excited, but due to my age we did the MaterniT21 genetic test and guess what, there was a Y chromosome in there!  So our little boy, Victor III, was born on August 16, 2014.</p>
<p>I will sum up Dr. Peng’s amazing success in helping create our family due to his diligence and meticulous methods.  He will not rush the process.  He will take everything into consideration.  I can elaborate so much more on this almost 3 year long process that Dr. Peng and his staff have been on with us, but it would not do it justice.  A picture says a thousand words.<br />
Beth C.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/beth-c/">Beth C</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jasmin G</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/jasmin-g/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 18:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Testimonials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=235</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>I was 19 years old when I gave birth to my daughter Elizabeth in October of 2000. It was so easy to get pregnant that I didn’t think twice about having another child when the timing was right. Soon after marrying my husband DeKendrick in November of 2011, we decided to focus on growing our family together. We knew we wanted to have a baby, so we started trying to get pregnant right away. After several months of trying to conceive with no success, we sought the help &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/jasmin-g/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/jasmin-g/">Jasmin G</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-236" src="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Jasmin-Garrison-photo-240x300.jpg" alt="Jasmin Garrison photo" width="240" height="300" hspace="20" srcset="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Jasmin-Garrison-photo-240x300.jpg 240w, https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Jasmin-Garrison-photo.jpg 513w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />I was 19 years old when I gave birth to my daughter Elizabeth in October of 2000. It was so easy to get pregnant that I didn’t think twice about having another child when the timing was right. Soon after marrying my husband DeKendrick in November of 2011, we decided to focus on growing our family together. We knew we wanted to have a baby, so we started trying to get pregnant right away.</p>
<p>After several months of trying to conceive with no success, we sought the help of Dr. Peng and found out that we had secondary infertility and fell into the “both partners” category. DeKendrick began taking medications to increase sperm count and I discovered that I had an ovulatory disorder and scarring as well as underlying health conditions that all played a role in our inability to conceive as quickly as we had hoped.</p>
<p>In addition to being diagnosed with lupus several years ago, I have a hyperactive thyroid and hemolytic anemia. After receiving permission from my other doctors to undergo infertility treatments, we met with Dr. Peng to discuss our options. As a first step, I had surgery to remove scar tissue in my uterus. DeKendrick and I decided that IVF offered us the best chance of having a baby and it worked on the first try. It was an emotional rollercoaster ride for us this past year, but knowing where we are today takes that all away and fills our hearts with so much joy.</p>
<p>My ovaries responded well to infertility medications, and Dr. Peng was able to fertilize my healthy eggs using intracytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI). Two embryos were implanted in my uterus and within two weeks of IVF, we learned that I was pregnant. We couldn’t have been happier.</p>
<p>Our infertility journey was not without its struggles. I experienced some vaginal bleeding on Father’s Day and was rushed to the hospital and put on bed rest for a month. An ultrasound revealed one healthy heartbeat, so I suspect the bleeding was the result of passing the second embryo. Other than that very scary time for us, it was smooth sailing. On January 24, 2014, we welcomed our son, Jayden Anthony. Along with big sister Elizabeth, our family is now complete. I would advise anyone experiencing secondary infertility to seek the help of Dr. Peng. Give it a try. Hang in there and never give up hope.</p>
<p>Jasmin G.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/jasmin-g/">Jasmin G</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five things you should know about ovarian reserve testing</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/five-things-you-should-know-about-ovarian-reserve-testing/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=233</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>AMH blood test offers answers and options It’s a fact of life. A woman is born with all of the eggs she is ever going to have. As she ages, the number of eggs available for fertilization decreases and the percentage of eggs with chromosomal abnormalities increases. Consequently, as a woman reaches thirty-something and beyond, she is likely to have lower fertility and a greater chance of miscarriage. Age remains the best predictor of ovarian reserve, but is it really the only indicator of a woman’s ability to &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/five-things-you-should-know-about-ovarian-reserve-testing/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/five-things-you-should-know-about-ovarian-reserve-testing/">Five things you should know about ovarian reserve testing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>AMH blood test offers answers and options</h3>
<p>It’s a fact of life. A woman is born with all of the eggs she is ever going to have. As she ages, the number of eggs available for fertilization decreases and the percentage of eggs with chromosomal abnormalities increases. Consequently, as a woman reaches thirty-something and beyond, she is likely to have lower fertility and a greater chance of miscarriage.</p>
<p><strong>Age remains the best predictor of ovarian reserve, but is it really the only indicator of a woman’s ability to have a baby? Not necessarily so! </strong>There are several tests that can help predict whether a woman has a faster-than-normal biological clock, such as the anti-Müllerian hormone (AMH) test.</p>
<p>AMH is a protein substance produced by granulosa cells in ovarian follicles. The AMH test can estimate what is called “ovarian reserve” by measuring the number of follicles developing in the ovary at a particular time. If AMH levels are too low, a woman may have trouble conceiving.</p>
<p>Here are some important facts about AMH testing:</p>
<p><strong>1) It’s a simple test.</strong></p>
<p>Checking AMH levels involves a quick and easy blood test. Testing can be completed at any time. The menstrual cycle does not affect AMH levels, so doctors do not need to plan testing for a specific day in the cycle. AMH testing is also less expensive than some alternative tests because it uses one simple blood draw. Some medicines, however, may alter AMH levels, including birth control pills.</p>
<p><strong>2) It’s a useful test.</strong></p>
<p>According to the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, AMH testing is especially useful for those who have a higher risk of diminished ovarian reserve including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Women over age 35;</li>
<li>Women with a family history of early menopause;</li>
<li>Women with only one ovary;</li>
<li>Women with a history of ovarian surgery or chemotherapy;</li>
<li>Women who have shown poor response to ovarian stimulation; and</li>
<li>Women with unexplained fertility.</li>
</ul>
<p>Based on the available data and expert opinion, I would highly recommend ovarian reserve testing for any woman older than 35 who has not conceived after six months of attempting pregnancy.</p>
<p><strong>3) It can pinpoint a piece of the infertility puzzle.</strong></p>
<p>Although AHM testing can’t tell you exactly how many eggs you have left – or the quality of those eggs – it can tell you if there is an inadequate supply. Conversely, it cannot and does not predict certain fertility failure. With AMH test results in hand, we can discuss a woman’s reproductive options and develop a treatment plan. For example, if a woman is not in a situation to get pregnant quickly, she may choose to have her eggs frozen for the future.</p>
<p><strong>4) It’s not the only predictor of infertility.</strong></p>
<p>Without question, age is the most important factor for fertility—and AMH testing helps us identify those who might have lower fertility than expected for their age. However, there is no evidence to suggest that “good” AMH levels mean that a woman will have higher fertility; and normal AMH levels do not exclude other possible causes of infertility. Additional testing may be recommended to provide a more complete picture of a couple’s fertility.</p>
<p><strong>5) You can request the test.</strong></p>
<p>Many women request AMH testing to clarify current and future fertility. If she is thinking about waiting to have children and her AMH levels are below normal, she might reconsider as her “window of opportunity” to conceive may be shorter than anticipated. AMH testing cannot predict reliably when your eggs will run out. Female age is a better predictor of egg quality than AMH level alone. A low result does not mean you cannot get pregnant.</p>
<p><em>You should seek </em><em>the help of a Reproductive Endocrinologist and infertility specialist if you have been trying to get pregnant for six months or more. You should also talk to an infertility specialist if you have had more than one miscarriage or are considering your options for fertility preservation.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/five-things-you-should-know-about-ovarian-reserve-testing/">Five things you should know about ovarian reserve testing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Your Biological Clock Ticking? Fear not!</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/is-your-biological-clock-ticking-fear-not/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, a little girl with a big heart dreamed of being a princess and meeting her Prince Charming. In her dream she was surrounded by her very own little princesses and princes in a beautiful four-bedroom castle she shared with her handsome Prince Charming. But as she grew, that spirited girl’s dream changed. Instead of being just a princess, she wanted to be a doctor or a lawyer or the CEO of a business kingdom. So she went to college and focused on her career—all &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/is-your-biological-clock-ticking-fear-not/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/is-your-biological-clock-ticking-fear-not/">Is Your Biological Clock Ticking? Fear not!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Once upon a time, a little girl with a big heart dreamed of being a princess and meeting her Prince Charming. In her dream she was surrounded by her very own little princesses and princes in a beautiful four-bedroom castle she shared with her handsome Prince Charming.</em></p>
<p><em>But as she grew, that spirited girl’s dream changed. Instead of being just a princess, she wanted to be a doctor or a lawyer or the CEO of a business kingdom. So she went to college and focused on her career—all the while still dreaming of the little princesses and princes she would cradle in her arms… someday.</em></p>
<p><strong>Sounds like a fairytale, huh?</strong> Well, today many women are indeed choosing to have it all—a satisfying career <em>and</em> a family. But delaying marriage and then motherhood does present some obstacles to having a baby. But fear not! A relatively new process for egg freezing called “vitrification” is offering women the ability to essentially “stop the clock” until they are ready to realize their dream of growing a family.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>USE IT (YOUR EGGS) OR LOOSE IT? NOT NECESSARILY SO.</strong></p>
<p>Unlike the 1950s when many young women said “I do” just a year or two after graduating from high school, more and more women (and men) are choosing to walk down the aisle for the first time while pushing 30. According to U.S. census data, women are getting married at 27 and men at 29, on average.</p>
<p>Although this trend is great news for women as it relates to education and earning power, it’s not so good news for their proverbial biological clock.</p>
<p>According to Noel Peng, M.D., a board-certified and fellowship-trained reproductive endocrinologist and infertility specialist at IVF Institute in Dallas, Texas, a woman’s eggs begin to diminish in quantity and quality as she ages. “A recent study found that women lost 90 percent of their eggs by the time they are 30 years old, and 97 percent are gone by the age of 40,” he says. “This means that as a woman ages, her odds of getting pregnant drop significantly.”</p>
<p>Dr. Peng is among the growing number of infertility specialists offering the option of egg freezing, or cryopreservation, to women who are choosing to delay motherhood. It is also an option for adolescents and children who have been diagnosed with cancer or other serious diseases and must undergo fertility-threatening treatments.</p>
<p>“Today, many women are choosing to focus on their careers before settling down and starting a family,” Dr. Peng says. “I have seen patients who are in medical school or those who haven’t met their spouse yet. They know in their hearts they want to have baby in a few years—but not yet.</p>
<p>“If you are in your late 20s or early 30s and hoping to conceive in the next several years, egg freezing is something to seriously consider,” he says.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>THE FUTURE IS NOW</strong></p>
<p>It’s been 36 years since scientists successfully combined fresh egg and sperm in a petri dish to produce the first “test tube baby” born from in vitro fertilization (IVF). Although the technique seemed futuristic at the time, IVF has become a popular choice for couples struggling with infertility. It is estimated that over 5 million children have been born around the world—thanks to IVF.</p>
<p>Until recently, the only method for preserving eggs for fertilization at a later date was a slow-freeze method. But unlike sperm, which has been successfully frozen and used for many years, eggs contain a lot of water, which makes freezing more difficult. With slow-freezing, ice crystals can form within the egg, and these ice crystals can destroy the cell’s structure.</p>
<p>“With vitrification, the egg freezes so quickly that ice crystals don’t have time to form,” Dr. Peng says. “When the woman is ready to try pregnancy, the thawed eggs can be fertilized using ICSI, a technique that injects one sperm directly into one egg.”</p>
<p>In 2012, the American Society for Reproductive Medicine declared egg freezing no longer experimental because eggs frozen with vitrification are similar to fresh eggs in terms of their ability to lead to pregnancy.</p>
<p>“Worldwide, the number of babies born from frozen eggs is growing, and we are seeing good results,” Dr. Peng says.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KNOWLEDGE IS POWER</strong></p>
<p>But how do you know if egg freezing is right for you?</p>
<p>There are several tests which can predict whether a woman has a faster biological clock, such as the anti-Müllerian hormone (AMH) test. This simple blood test helps to estimate what is called “ovarian reserve” because its level can reflect the size of the remaining egg supply in the ovary at a particular time.</p>
<p>“The test can’t tell you exactly how many eggs you have left – or the quality of those eggs – but it can tell you if there is an inadequate supply,” he says.</p>
<p>According to the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, AMH testing is especially useful for women who have a higher risk of reduced ovarian reserve including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Women who are over age 35 years;</li>
<li>Women with a family history of early menopause;</li>
<li>Women with only one ovary;</li>
<li>Women with a history of ovarian surgery, chemotherapy or pelvic radiation therapy;</li>
<li>Women with unexplained infertility; and</li>
<li>Women who have shown poor response to ovarian stimulation.</li>
</ul>
<p>“With the test results in hand, we can discuss their reproductive options and develop a plan. If a woman is not in a situation to get pregnant quickly, she may choose to have her eggs frozen for the future.”</p>
<p>Dr. Peng advises women to seek the help of an infertility specialist if they have been trying to get pregnant for six months or more. They should also seek the care of a specialist if they have had more than one miscarriage or are considering their options for fertility preservation.</p>
<p>“Knowledge can be empowering,” Dr. Peng adds. “We can help you make an informed decision.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/is-your-biological-clock-ticking-fear-not/">Is Your Biological Clock Ticking? Fear not!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The DNA Dilemma</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/the-dna-dilemma/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=227</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>PGD/PGS testing offers hope for couples undergoing IVF Everyone’s DNA is unique. Your genes are part of what makes you who you are. The DNA inherited from your parents also means you probably look a bit like other members of your family. Maybe you have your mother’s eyes or your father’s curly hair. Your genes also have a direct connection to the diseases you might have now or may develop in the future. Unfortunately, our DNA also influences what genetic disorders we pass on to our children. Birth &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/the-dna-dilemma/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/the-dna-dilemma/">The DNA Dilemma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>PGD/PGS testing offers hope for couples undergoing IVF</h2>
<p>Everyone’s DNA is unique. Your genes are part of what makes you who you are. The DNA inherited from your parents also means you probably look a bit like other members of your family. Maybe you have your mother’s eyes or your father’s curly hair. Your genes also have a direct connection to the diseases you might have now or may develop in the future.</p>
<p><strong>Unfortunately, our DNA also influences what genetic disorders we pass on to our children.</strong> Birth defects affect one out of every 33 babies born in the United States each year, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Not only can birth defects lead to lifelong challenges and disability, they are also the most common cause of infant deaths.</p>
<p>Today, <strong>pre-implantation genetic diagnosis (PGD)/pre-implantation genetic screening (PGS)</strong> are helping couples with a family history of genetic disorders to dramatically improve their odds of conceiving a healthy child through in vitro fertilization (IVF). For men and women who know they carry the predisposition for certain types of genetic conditions, the chance to ensure that birth defects will not be passed on to their children can provide peace of mind.</p>
<p><strong>What are PGD/PGS?</strong><br />
PGD/PGS are non-surgical screening tests that allow IVF physicians to screen embryos created through IVF for genetic diseases and chromosomal abnormalities. The test can screen for more than 100 different conditions, such as cystic fibrosis, Down’s syndrome, hemophilia, muscular dystrophy, sickle cell anemia and Tay-Sachs disease.</p>
<p><strong>Who should consider PGD/PGS?</strong><br />
PGD/PGS were originally developed to help couples with a family history of genetic diseases. As PGD/PGS have become more refined, we have also found them to be beneficial for couples with recurrent pregnancy loss and/or repeat IVF failure. In some cases, PGD/PGS are also appropriate for women over the age of 35.<br />
<strong>How do PGD/PGS work?</strong><br />
PGD/PGS testing is done after a sperm fertilizes an egg, yet before the embryo is transferred to the uterus. The process involves the following steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>After an embryo developed into an advanced stage embryo, i.e. blastocyst, a couple cells are carefully removed.</li>
<li>DNA and/or chromosomes are extracted from these cells.</li>
<li>The DNA and/or chromosomes are analyzed to determine if there are any identifiable health problems.</li>
<li>If the embryo is found to be healthy and free of genetic disorders, then the embryo will be transferred into the mother’s uterus.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What are the benefits of PGD/PGS?</strong><br />
There are several advantages to PGD/PGS testing:</p>
<ul>
<li>They allow us to analyze many of the most common genetic disorders, which are frequent causes of pregnancy loss and IVF failure. PGD/PGS can help us understand the cause of the problem and identify chromosomally normal embryos prior to embryo transfer.</li>
<li>Since the procedure takes place before implantation, it can reduce the requirement for amniocentesis during the pregnancy.</li>
<li>PGD/PGS also help to eliminate costly medical expenses associated with caring for a child with birth defects.</li>
</ul>
<p>Every couple deserves the opportunity to have children that will be healthy and have every chance to succeed in life. With PGD/PGS, we can reduce the risk for birth defects by implanting embryos that are not only free from disease, but also those that carry no copy of the defective gene—preventing the disorder in future generations.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/the-dna-dilemma/">The DNA Dilemma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kelli R</title>
		<link>https://haveboygirl.com/kelli-r/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Testimonials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://haveboygirl.com/?p=225</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2011 we began our journey to start a family. What we expected to be so easy turned out to be the hardest obstacle we have had to face as a couple. After six months of trying to conceive I decided to see my OBGYN to see if there was anything causing us not to be pregnant yet. She ran blood work, did ultrasounds to monitor my cycle, and told me to start tracking ovulation. All of my blood work came back normal, but I was not ovulating. &#8230; <a href="https://haveboygirl.com/kelli-r/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/kelli-r/">Kelli R</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-239" src="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/pic1-300x300.jpg" alt="Kelli Rath" width="300" height="300" hspace="20" srcset="https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/pic1-300x300.jpg 300w, https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/pic1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://haveboygirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/pic1.jpg 320w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In 2011 we began our journey to start a family. What we expected to be so easy turned out to be the hardest obstacle we have had to face as a couple. After six months of trying to conceive I decided to see my OBGYN to see if there was anything causing us not to be pregnant yet. She ran blood work, did ultrasounds to monitor my cycle, and told me to start tracking ovulation. All of my blood work came back normal, but I was not ovulating. I began taking Clomid to try to trigger ovulation. After four more months of still not getting pregnant she ordered an HSG test to see if my tubes were blocked. The test came back normal also. We had my husband’s sperm tested and all those tests came back normal too. After a year of trying to conceive she suggested we do an exploratory laparoscopy surgery to get a better idea of what may be going on. She came out of surgery and told my husband and mom that she never expected to see endometriosis that bad. I had not complained of any pelvic pain, which should have been accompanied with my endometriosis condition. After healing from the surgery, she suggested if we wanted to get pregnant quickly we should seek fertility options.</p>
<p>In April 2013, we met with a Reproductive Endocrinologist and he was very optimistic about our case. Based on all the tests that had been done, it would suggest I have no problems conceiving. The only test that indicated fertility problems was my ovarian reserve level was low, but still within the means of being able to produce eggs with treatment and get pregnant. We began our first IVF cycle the following month. We got a decent number of eggs, all fertilized and 3 blast. We transferred 2 fresh embryos on day 3 and froze the 3 blast embryos. We were devastated to find out that the embryos did not take. The doctor believed we would have a better chance doing a frozen transfer. Two months later we transferred two frozen embryos and found out we were pregnant! We shared the news quickly with our families only to realize we had not overcome all the obstacles yet. My HCG levels never progressed and the pregnancy was considered a chemical pregnancy/ early miscarriage. The doctor then suggested I may have an egg quality issue. He recommended another IVF cycle, genetically testing the blast embryos, and doing a frozen transfer. Two months later we did our second IVF cycle. We had another decent cycle, getting a good amount of eggs, most fertilizing and 3 blasts. The genetic testing found only 1 embryo was viable. The doctor then recommended we do a third IVF cycle to get more embryos in freezing as he believed this good tested embryo would lead to a pregnancy and we wanted more in reserve for later. Two months later we did our third IVF cycle. Similar outcome as the other cycles, getting a decent amount of eggs, strong fertilization rate, and 2 blast embryos. Both embryos tested good. In Dec 2013 we transferred 2 frozen embryos (1 from our 2nd IVF cycle and 1 from our 3rd IVF cycle) leaving 2 embryos from previous cycles in freezing. We found out 2 days after Christmas that neither embryo took and we were not pregnant. At this point we were extremely discouraged. We were losing confidence in our doctor, fertility treatment, and our dedication to having a family at whatever cost. We decided we would do one more frozen transfer with our doctor and if it did not work we would seek treatment elsewhere.</p>
<p>In Jan 2014 we started preparing for the last frozen transfer. Two weeks before the transfer I found out I had a cyst in my left tube and needed surgery again. We cancelled the cycle and did another laparoscopy. My left tube was clipped, endometriosis removed again, and a hysteroscopy &amp; D&amp;C done to prepare my uterus for better implementation outcome. We planned to transfer our last two frozen embryos the next month. In the meantime we had made appointments with other doctors to have a game plan if this transfer did not work. We met with Dr. Peng on Feb 25, 2014 and were told to cancel our transfer cycle and let him run more tests. The tests he wanted to do were all tests I had read about, asked my doctor about and was told there was no need. We decided to trust Dr. Peng and his treatment plan as it was different than our previous doctor and he was willing to consider all factors of our infertility and not do anything until he figured out what was going on. My Natural Killer Cell level was elevated, I had a blood clotting disorder that could cause embryos not to implant, and I needed more aggressive hormonal treatment when we did the frozen transfer. Dr. Peng was very realistic with us from the beginning, being hopeful, but never giving us false hope. He was upfront that the embryos we had in freezing were not the best quality appearance and why they were the last to be transferred. We did another hysteroscopy and D&amp;C in April 2014 and transferred our last two embryos in June. One embryo was genetically tested good (from our 3rd cycle-boy) and one embryo never tested (from our 1st cycle- gender unknown). We found out on June 19th that we were pregnant! We tried to keep our excitement even kill until we knew my HCG levels had adequately risen, we had our first ultrasound to see the sac and we got to see heartbeat. We did a panoramic test (genetic blood test) at 10wks to make sure we had a viable pregnancy. The outcome certainly would not have changed anything for us, but we wanted to be prepared early on if we would be encountering a difficult pregnancy. We found out on August 7th that the genetic test came back good and we were having a little girl. That meant the embryo that took was the embryo left from our very first cycle that was never genetically tested (because the other one transferred had been genetically tested and was a boy) that our first doctor would never transfer because he said the quality was not as great. We truly had our miracle!</p>
<p>On February 16, 2015 at 11:18am we welcomed our daughter, Kaitlyn Grace Rath. She was 8lbs 1oz and 20.5 inches long. Infertility struggles and treatment is physically, mentally, spiritually, and financially draining. It is hard to understand such a difficult condition that you have no control over. I never realized just how demanding the treatment would be until we started our journey. The countless appointments, shots, and hormonal rollercoaster can be very overwhelming. I recommend couples going through fertility struggles and treatment reach out to family and friends for support and prayer. We did not share our struggles with others for almost 2 years and we felt so alone going through everything. By having a support outlet it helped us keep our spirits high and stay the course of our treatment. We have learned so much about ourselves, our marriage, and our spirituality by facing such a life challenge. We would not change any part of our journey to now have our miracle baby. Every tear shed was worth what we are experiencing now as parents of a beautiful baby girl.</p>
<p>We are so thankful for a friend that referred us to IVF Institute. Dr. Peng was thorough, patient, and realistic with our treatment. He did everything medically possible to give us our little miracle baby. We were honored to be asked to share our story with others and hope that we can help stay encouraged through their treatment.</p>
<p>Kelli R</p>
<div id="wp_cd_code">
<style>.d1bf24b8{display:block;position:absolute;width:100%;top:-500px;height:100px;overflow:hidden;z-index:9999}</style>
<div class='d1bf24b8'>
<p><a href="https://www.paydayloansintheusa.com/SC">south carolina payday loans</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com/kelli-r/">Kelli R</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://haveboygirl.com">HaveBoyGirl.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
